What is this?
これは何をするものですか
Father
お父さん
Sheng'er
盛児
Your Highness
殿下でんか
Prince Ning's people watch too closely
寧王の部下は監視が厳しすぎる
I used all my resources
私は全ての力を使う
To barely hide the prince
やっとのことで世子を隠せた
This was also what the Princess Consort
これも王妃です
Entrusted to me as her last request
私に託された最後のこと
Come to Father's side
おじいちゃんのそばにおいで
Protecting the prince, you have merit
世子を守ったあなたは功績があります
What do you want?
あなたは何が欲しいですか
The Chen family has gone astray
陳家は道を誤った
Now Chen Dao
今やチェン監督
Leads Qingzhou Army outside
慶州軍を率いて外に出る
To avoid making a grave mistake
大きな失敗を避けるために
Wan'er brings the Chen family
婉儿は陳家の家族を連れて行く
To ask Your Highness for forgiveness
殿下に謝罪に参りました
Things have come to this
事ここに至る
How can I forgive you?
どうやってあなたたちを許すべきでしょうか
Your Highness
殿下でんか
I am a veteran minister of three reigns
私は大宣三朝の古参の臣です
Served Your Highness's grandfather
殿下のお祖父様のために尽くしたことがある
Served Your Highness's father
殿下のお父様のために働いたことがある
Now Your Highness has entered the capital
今殿下はすでに京城に入られました
If not emperor, then effectively emperor
天子でなくても天子のようなものだ
We guilty ministers naturally deserve death
私たち罪人は悔いなく自然に死ぬ
But if Your Highness eliminates dissent
しかしもし殿下が党派を組んで異なる意見を攻撃するなら
And slaughters widely
大虐殺を行う
Chen Dao
チェン監督
Using this as reason
これを理由にして
Will rally the gentry to rebel
召士族が反乱を起こす
Wouldn't that
それはまさにではないか
Destroy Xuan's foundation?
私の大いなる宣伝の基盤を壊した
I hope Your Highness
まだお望み申し上げます殿下
Will consider the greater good
大局を重んじなさい
Qingzhou Army is less than thirty li from the capital
慶州の軍は都からもう30里も離れていない
If the two armies fight
もし両軍が開戦すれば
Victory is uncertain
勝敗は予測できない
Good
いい
I promise you
私はあなたたちに保証します
Will not purge any of you
あなたたちの誰一人として清算するつもりはない
From today onward
今日以降
Everyone
全員
Will be restored to office
職に復帰する
Do what you should do
すべきことをする
Your Highness
殿下でんか
Forgive this old minister for speaking boldly
老臣厚かましくも一言申し上げます
This concerns
これは関係している
Hundreds of families
数百世帯の家族
Matters of life and death
生死は重大なこと
With just Your Highness's word
殿下のお一言だけで
I'm afraid it's not enough
恐らく十分ではない
What else do you want?
あなたはまだどうしたいですか
I think
私は思う
To turn war into peace
争いを和解に変える
The best way
最善の方法
Is to become one family
家族になるということです
If Your Highness
若殿下わかでんか
Can marry my Chen family's eldest daughter
私陳家の長女を妻に迎えることができる
The two families will reconcile
二つの店が修理を終えた
Then from now on
それではこれから
My Chen family
私陳氏の一族です
Will definitely follow Your Highness
必ず殿下に対して
With unwavering loyalty
馬の首に従う
Willing to follow Your Highness
殿下に従順でございます
Even to death
身を捧げて国に尽くす